Guide to the Allan Todd Sagraves papers, 1960-1976 and undated RL.11752
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Allan Todd Sagraves papers
1960-1976 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sagraves, Allan T.
RL.11752
2.0 Linear Feet
Todd Sagraves was Professor Emiritus of Business Education at Central Connecticut State University. Collection consists primarily of 16mm films and film clips of television commercials, along with explanatory documentation for two films, How to Sell Creatively (produced by Dartnell Corporation) and Television Advertising Commercials (edited by Sagraves), and other printed materials. Companies represented in the collection include Beech-Nut, Bristol-Myers, Coca-Cola, Colgate, General Foods, Datsun (Nissan), Nestle, Procter & Gamble, Sara Lee and the Television Bureau of Advertising. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Print materials; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Todd Sagraves was Professor Emiritus of Business Education at Central Connecticut State University. Born 1930, Louisville Kentucky. Korean war-era service U.S. Air Force. AA Boise Junior College; BA University of Northern Colorado; MA University of Pittsburgh; graduate study University of Connecticut. Professor of Business and Marketing Education, Central Connecticut State University 1961-1992. Died 2019 Apex, North Carolina.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Provenance
The Allan Todd Sagraves papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2004.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Archie Boston papers
Carl Spielvogel papers
James Webb Young papers
John Benjamin Harris papers
Kensinger Jones papers
Lester Wunderman papers
Richard W. Pollay papers
Walter Weir papers
Collection Overview
Collection consists primarily of 16mm films and film clips of television commercials, along with explanatory documentation for two films, How to Sell Creatively (produced by Dartnell Corporation) and Television Advertising Commercials (edited by Sagraves), and other printed materials. Companies represented in the collection include Beech-Nut, Bristol-Myers, Coca-Cola, Colgate, General Foods, Datsun (Nissan), Nestle, Procter & Gamble, Sara Lee and the Television Bureau of Advertising. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Bristol-Myers Company; Coca-Cola Company; Colgate-Palmolive Company; General Foods Corporation; Nissan Motor Corporation in U.S.A.; Nestlé; Procter & Gamble Company; Sara Lee Corporation
- Print Materials, 1960-1971; 1
  - Annotated bibliography for 16mm television advertising film, 1971 (Box 1)
  - How to Sell Creatively--Meeting Guide, 1960 (Box 1)
  - How to Sell Creatively--Promotional poster, approximately 1960 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Television Bureau of Advertising--Print Converter, 1963 (Box 1)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1960-1976 and undated; 2
  - AMC Gremlin--Tank of Gas, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-001)
  - American Express :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-002)
  - Animation, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-003)
    Scope and Contents
    Dove dishwashing liquid, Absorbine Jr., Vote toothpaste
  - Arco Flair Glasses :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-004)
  - Ballantine Beer :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-005)
  - Bayer :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-006)
  - Beech Nut bubble gum, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-007)
  - Beech Nut cartoon :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-008)
  - Borden/Drake's Cakes :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-009)
  - Bristol Myers :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-010)
  - Bristol Myers :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-011)
  - Burger Chef cartoon :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-012)
  - Chevrolet :10, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-013)
  - Citgo :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-014)
  - Coca-Cola #2 :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-015)
  - Coca-Cola/Minute Maid: Bing Crosby :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-016)
  - Coca-Cola/Whipped Cream: Plastic Bottles :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-017)
  - Colgate :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-018)
  - Colgate Piggyback :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-019)
  - Crest: Mistake, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-020)
  - Crest: New Family, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-021)
  - Datsun :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-022)
  - Datsun :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-023)
  - Datsun Really Something :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-024)
  - Drama, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-025)
    Alka-Seltzer, Beech Nut
  - Drama, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-026)
    Vitalis, Imperial Margarine
  - Drama, Cartoon, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-027)
    Morris Nine Lives, Captain Crunch, Chunky Candy
  - Fiat :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-028)
  - General Electric drama :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-029)
  - General Foods :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-030)
  - General Foods Brim :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-031)
  - General Foods Grape Nuts :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-032)
  - General Foods Orange Tang :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-033)
  - General Mills cartoon :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-034)
  - Gillette, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-035)
  - Heart Association of Connecticut PSA :30 from Gunsmoke, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-036)
  - Heinz spaghetti sauce, Squibb drama, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-037)
  - Household Finance cartoon :10, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-038)
  - Johnson & Johnson piggyback :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-039)
  - Julie Andrews PSA, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-040)
  - Kellogg's bicentennial cartoon :30, 1976 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-041)
  - Kimberly0Clark diapers drama :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-042)
  - Maxwell House coffee :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-043)
  - National TB Christmas Seals animation :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-044)
  - Nestle candy :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-045)
  - Nestle Quik, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-046)
  - Oh Henry :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-047)
  - Pampers Concert drama, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-048)
  - Porsche-Audi :25, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-049)
  - Post Pebbles Chocolate Factory cartoon (Barney and Fred Flintstone) :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-050)
  - Procter & Gamble Crest/Ivory :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-051)
  - Procter & Gamble Duncan Hines drama :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-052)
  - Procter & Gamble Ivory Snow demo :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-053)
  - Proctor Silex :28, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-054)
  - Promo Adam 12, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-055)
  - PSA Child Entrapment Prevention animation :60, 1970 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-056)
  - Q Tips Monkey :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-057)
  - Ralston Picadily English drama :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-058)
  - Sara Lee 2 :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-059)
  - Sara Lee drama :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-060)
  - Sara Lee drama :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-061)
  - TB Seals PSA animation :30, 1972 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-062)
  - Uncle Ben's personality :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-063)
  - Uniroyal :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-064)
  - Untitled, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-065)
  - USDA Pesticide PSA animation :30, 1970 (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-066)
  - Vick's Clearasil drama/demo :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-067)
  - Warner-Lambert Trident drama :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-068)
  - Yardman Rider cartoon :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11752-F16-069)
  - How to Sell Creatively, 1960 (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11752-F16-070)
  - Television Advertising Film, approximately 1971 (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11752-F16-071)